<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Biggus Datum</title>
    <link>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Biggus Datum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Tiago Cipriano Pires</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 17:50:33 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://biggusdatum.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zen Buddhists say</title>
      <link>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/pensamentos/zen-buddhists-say/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 17:50:33 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/pensamentos/zen-buddhists-say/</guid>
      <description>Zen Buddhists say you need three things: Something to love, something to hope for and something to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quando eu morrer...</title>
      <link>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/pensamentos/quando-morrer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 18:53:38 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/pensamentos/quando-morrer/</guid>
      <description>Quando eu morrer e sempre que quiserem me celebrar no dia do meu aniversário, deixem-me no cemitério meio frango de churrasco com piri-piri e batata frita - MAS DAS VERDADEIRAS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download IPMA Open Data</title>
      <link>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/ipma/download-ipma-open-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 09:12:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/ipma/download-ipma-open-data/</guid>
      <description>Esta manhã fiz um programeta para fazer download dos dados do IPMA. Neste momento apenas vai buscar os dados de uma estação, de Tavira.&#xA;Pontos chave:&#xA;escrito em Kotlin Sqlite para guardar os dados SqlDelight como interface para a base de dados Ainda sou muito verdinho nisto do Kotlin. O Kotlin das duas linguagens de programação que decidi aprender em 2024. A única outra coisa que fiz em Kotlin antes foi um jogo das damas, usando o MinMax (com cortes alfa-beta).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IPMA Open Data</title>
      <link>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/ipma/ipma-open-data-project-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 07:11:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/ipma/ipma-open-data-project-overview/</guid>
      <description>Há anos que coleciono os dados da estação metereológica mais perto da horta, em Tavira. Têm sido publicados em PDF (wtf?) há anos - pelos menos desde 2006. O problema é que (1) fazer o parsing de um PDF é complicado, (2) mudaram a estrutura um par de vezes e o pior (3) é que em certos meses talvez um sensor deve ter pifado e em vez de colocarem um zero ou string vazia saltaram a célula e portanto há linhas com menos colunas que outras.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re getting there</title>
      <link>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/were-getting-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 20:42:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/were-getting-there/</guid>
      <description>Just edited the about page. We&amp;rsquo;re getting there. Still need to think about navigation. Maybe push these posts to the side and let the collections or pages be the center of the page. Not sure yet, but we&amp;rsquo;re getting there. I&amp;rsquo;m quite enjoying the creation of this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s OK not to always have an opinion</title>
      <link>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/quotes/its-ok-not-to-have-an-opinion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 18:20:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/quotes/its-ok-not-to-have-an-opinion/</guid>
      <description>You always own the option of having no opinion. There is never any need to get worked up or to trouble your soul about things you can&amp;rsquo;t control. These things are not asking to be judged by you. Leave them alone.&#xA;&amp;ndash; Marcus Aurelius</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serenity Now</title>
      <link>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/quotes/serenity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 18:18:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/quotes/serenity/</guid>
      <description>God grant me the serenity to accept the things I cannot change. Courage to change the things that I can. And wisdom to know the difference.&#xA;&amp;ndash; Marcus Aurelius</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to deal with depression</title>
      <link>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/quotes/depression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:01:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/quotes/depression/</guid>
      <description>Put depression on your todo list so you never get to it&#xA;&amp;ndash; Tiago Forte</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doesn&#39;t know how to keep know how</title>
      <link>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/fwfoc/know-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:14:58 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/fwfoc/know-how/</guid>
      <description>A friend works for a company that, after acquiring a software company for millions just for their know-how, allowed them to work in a silo while integrating their software into the main data stream. Subsequently, the company proceeded to fire them all. Now, they can&amp;rsquo;t understand or perform the required maintenance on what has become essential software. Having none of the knowledge that cost millions to acquire, the company has decided to fix this issue by hiring external consultants instead of relying on in-house developers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s this all about</title>
      <link>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/kickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 21:14:58 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://biggusdatum.com/posts/kickstart/</guid>
      <description>Digital garden, ramblings and others. Appologies with the mix of languages, but that&amp;rsquo;s just how my mind works.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
